So now we're pretty clear on how we use those basic prepositions to talk about times.
所以现在我们很清楚我们如何使用这些基本介词来谈论时间。
Now we can talk about days months weeks dates years decades using often these three at on and in.
现在我们可以经常使用这三个 at on 和 in 来谈论几天几个月几周日期几年几十年。
Now at is for a specific time just like when we say six thirty.
现在是一个特定的时间，就像我们说六点三十一样。
But add is often used for a point within a year or a month or a week.
但是add通常用于一年或一个月或一周内的一个点。
For example at the beginning of June at the beginning of next month.
比如下月初六月初。
OK.
好的。
At the end of the week we can use app for that.
在周末我们可以使用应用程序。
It's sort of a time point within a within a larger thing a larger unit.
这是一个更大的事物中的一个时间点，一个更大的单位。
OK how about on then on is actually more common when we're talking about days and days if it's an exact
好吧，当我们谈论几天和几天时，如果它是精确的，那么 on then on 实际上更常见
date we won't say at June 13th we say on June 13th on June 13th.
日期我们不会在 6 月 13 日说，我们会在 6 月 13 日说 6 月 13 日。
I flew home.
我飞回家了。
That's it.
而已。
There on June 13th.
6月13日在那里。
I flew home on February 20 seventh on July 6th on August 24th.
我在 2 月 20 日 7 月 6 日 7 月 7 日 8 月 24 日飞回家。
What ever.
任何。
Well we say a specific date.
好吧，我们说一个具体的日期。
We use on OK.
我们使用OK。
We also use on when we say for example the actual day of the week on Friday of last week or this week
当我们说例如上周的星期五或本周的实际星期几时，我们也使用 on
on Friday.
在周五。
I I have a match.
我有比赛。
Maybe you're a tennis player.
也许你是一名网球运动员。
When is your match is on Friday.
你的比赛是什么时候在星期五。
Oh OK.
哦好的。
What do you usually do on the weekend.
你通常在周末做什么。
Do you usually do on the weekend.
你通常在周末做。
What do you usually do on weekends.
你周末经常做什么。
So for a weekend even though it's two days some people consider it three days.
所以对于一个周末，即使它是两天，有些人认为它是三天。
We use on as well.
我们也使用 on 。
We don't use at for the weekends.
我们周末不使用 at。
We don't use in for the weekends.
我们周末不使用。
We don't stay in the weekends.
我们不在周末逗留。
We can stay in the week we can say during the week for the whole thing.
我们可以呆在一周内，我们可以在一周内说整个事情。
You could say during the weekend.
你可以说在周末。
But usually we say on the weekend and then in.
但通常我们说在周末然后在。
Is used for much larger things we'll say for example in April we need to book our hotel.
用于我们会说的更大的事情，例如在四月我们需要预订我们的酒店。
That's when we need to do it in April.
那是我们需要在四月做的时候。
So we're talking about the whole month of April.
所以我们谈论的是整个四月。
Whenever it happens.
每当它发生。
OK.
好的。
If it's a larger thing in 2014 I moved to Austria.
如果这是 2014 年更大的事情，我搬到了奥地利。
Why.
为什么。
Why not.
为什么不。
Why not move to Austria in 2014.
为什么不在 2014 年搬到奥地利。
I moved to Austria out in the 90s.
我在 90 年代搬到了奥地利。
Now we're talking about a decade which is a 10 year period in the 90s in the 80s in the 70s in the 60s.
现在我们谈论的是十年，即 90 年代到 80 年代到 70 年代到 60 年代的 10 年。
Well if we go back 100 years then we start and we need to start saying 18 70s 80s 90s 14 20s.
好吧，如果我们回到 100 年，那么我们开始，我们需要开始说 18 70 年代 80 年代 90 年代 14 20 年代。
But if we're talking about the the previous century then we just use 90s in the 90s in the 90s fashion
但如果我们谈论的是上个世纪，那么我们只是在 90 年代的 90 年代时尚中使用 90 年代
was weird.
很奇怪。
It's true.
这是真的。
I guess fashion is always weird when you look back though right.
我想当你回头看时，时尚总是很奇怪。
What I'm wearing now my hair probably will be weird very soon maybe it's weird now.
我现在穿的头发可能很快就会变得很奇怪，也许现在很奇怪。
I don't know.
我不知道。
All right.
好的。
So that's how we use at on and in when we're talking about days dates months years decades.
这就是我们在谈论日数月数年数十年时使用的方式。
Things like that.
像这样的东西。
Hope that's pretty easy to understand.
希望这很容易理解。
Should be.
应该。